robomongo.org 2019-12-14

# Robomongo

### Introduction

3T (which means 3T Software Labs Limited) respects your privacy. All information you give us is held with the utmost care and security. 3T is committed to protecting your privacy. If you’re visiting our websites, using our products and services, working with any of our teams, meeting us at events or applying for a role with us, this privacy policy sets out what data we collect, and how we use it. It also describes your rights regarding our use of your data.

Please take time to review this privacy policy as it sets out our privacy practices and tells you how we will treat your personal information. We do not sell, rent or loan any identifiable information regarding our customers to any third party. Only in the circumstances described within this Privacy Policy would we share your information with any third party.

Our use of personal data is in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).

### 1\. Identity of the controller

3T Software Labs Limited  
Newnham House  
Cambridge Business Park  
Cambridge CB4 0WZ  
United Kingdom

### 2\. Data processing on our Site

#### 2.1. Personal data

Pursuant to the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR“), personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

#### 2.2. General use of the Site

Insofar as you do not actively make personal data available to us, we do not store personal data while you use our Site except that our webserver(s) register all connections to the Site automatically and collects the following technical information about your visit:

  * Your IP address;
  * the name of the files accessed;
  * information about the transmission;
  * date and time of the connection;
  * the amount of data transmitted;
  * the requesting provider;
  * the referrer; and
  * the web browser/user agent.

We store this data in log files in order to ensure the safety and integrity of our IT-Systems. Additionally, we use your IP address only to enable communication with our Site. Both constitute our legitimate interests of us pursuant to Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. We store our log files for 8 weeks.

#### 2.3. Downloading our Software for free

You can download our Software without giving us any personal data. However, we strongly encourage you to provide us with some information about you and your company. Specifically, we ask you to give us your

  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Email address
  * Telephone Number
  * Company Name
  * How you heard about us
  * Your Team Size and
  * Whether you are using MongoDB in Production.

We use this data to get insights who our users are and for what purpose our software is used. Moreover we use this data to contact you [via telephone/ email] to provide you with guidance, support and helpful tips & tricks for our software and general information about our products and services. The legal basis is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes also constitutes our legitimate interests. If you agreed in receiving helpful information, we store your data until you object. Otherwise, we delete your data after 2 years.

#### 2.4. Buying our software

If you are a commercial user, you can buy our products directly from our Site. For this purpose we collect your

  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Company
  * Email address
  * Telephone number.
  * A billing address
  * Additional payment information depending on the payment method you choose

We use this information for the purposes of performance and conclusion of contract. The legal basis is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b) GDPR. Additionally, we are legally obliged to store certain data, which is included in contracts and invoices as well as in business letters or other documents relevant for taxation or accounting. The legal basis is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. c) GDPR. If you purchase the software for somebody else, we collect the customer’s name and the companies’ name. We only use this information to embed it into the license key. We store the data that is relevant for taxation and accounting for 11 years from the end of the year the contract is concluded in. Any other data is stored for 3 years after the end of the year the contract is concluded in.

#### 2.5. Registering a license

Before you are able to start using our Software, we ask you to give us your

First name, Last name and Email address

We will use this information in order to provide you with the possibility to manage your bought licenses so that you can, for example, see how many of your licenses are in use. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b) GDPR. Moreover, we will do license enquiries from time to time, in order to get an overview on the use of our licenses so that we can detect and prevent cases of license exploitation or fraud. This processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR and the aforementioned purpose constitutes the legitimate interests we pursue with it. Finally we may use your email address to contact you in the future for customer service and sales purposes, e.g. to inform you about renewal and upgrade options, which also constitutes our legitimate interests (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR).

You can unsubscribe from such emails directly inside the respective email or by letting us know at [privacy@studio3t.com](mailto:privacy@studio3t.com) at any time.

We store the aforementioned information for as long as you have a valid license. Additionally, we keep it for 3 more years after the end of the year your license expires in order to be able to make or defend ourselves against claims that arise from the use of the license or stand in connection with it in any way.

#### 2.6. Discounts

For certain groups of users, namely Startups, teachers, students, researchers and nonprofits, we offer special discounts on our products. To verify if you are entitled to receive such discount we collect:

If you apply for a Startup discount:

  * Your Name
  * Your Company Email
  * Company Name
  * Website
  * Establishment Date
  * Supporting Documents
  * Supporting Links (if applicable)

If you apply for a teacher, student or researcher discount:

  * Name
  * Email Address
  * Your role as teacher, student or researcher
  * Academic institution
  * Supporting documents (official documents verifying your status)

If you apply for a nonprofit discount:

  * Name
  * Email Address
  * Organization Name
  * Website
  * Supporting Documents (if applicable)

The legal basis for verifying whether you are entitled to a discount is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b) GDPR. Additionally, we use the data for the purposes described in Section 2.2.3. We store the data that is relevant for taxation and accounting for 11 years from the end of the year the contract is concluded in. Any other data is stored for 3 years after the end of the year the contract is concluded in. If you choose to receive our newsletter, we use your Name, and email address to provide you with the newest information about our products and services. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. a). GDPR. This data is stored until you withdraw your consent.

#### 2.7. Feedback & Support via our Site or the software

We enable you to contact us and ask us for support on our Site. For these purposes we collect your

  * First Name,
  * Last Name
  * Email address and
  * Your message to us.

Depending on the topic you request our help for, we may ask you for additional information to help us assist you (like diagnostic logs). We may share this with our product development teams to enable them to reproduce and fix product issues. 3T also maintains a presence on Twitter, Facebook, Youtube, and LinkedIn. We manage your interactions with us using Hootsuite as well as using social media platforms directly. If you send us a message via social media, we may include this in our CRM systems.

The legal basis for these processing is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest is to answer your questions and fulfill your requests. We store your data for 3 years.

Some of our products also include feedback mechanisms such as live chat. If you’re signed into the product, we’ll see your name and email address when you chat to us. Any information you send to us in the chat session will be shared with our product development and support teams. We store your data for 3 years.

#### 2.8. Newsletters and drip campaigns

We send newsletters, and onboarding and educational emails using HubSpot, MailChimp and SendGrid on the legal basis of Art. 6 par. 1 lit. a) GDPR. We store the data necessary for sending the newsletters until you withdraw your consent. We gather statistics around email opening and interaction using industry-standard technologies, including tracking pixels, to analyze the performance or email campaigns. We use data about your interactions with our emails as an indicator of your interest in our products. We may also use your interaction with our previous newsletters to send you more appropriate information in the future. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute our legitimate interests. We store your data for 3 years.

You can opt out of receiving these newsletters and drip campaigns at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in these emails, or sending an email to [privacy@studio3t.com](mailto:privacy@studio3t.com)

#### 2.9. Information sent to us when you use our products

Our products send usage and fault reporting information to us. We use this to:

  * Measure how many people are using the different versions of our products, and the different features within them.
  * Understand the environments in which our products are used (for example, the operating system version, MongoDB Server version, the amount of system memory and screen resolutions)
  * Measure the success of our sales and marketing operations
  * Guide product development decisions and improve our products
  * Assist you in your evaluation, purchasing, and renewal of our products

We use your basic environment and high-level usage data in conjunction with your records in our marketing and CRM systems. Your use of individual features is submitted anonymously and is not linked to your identity.

Some of our products allow you to submit error reports if something goes wrong. These contain logs and other diagnostic data, and you can choose to include your contact details and any additional information you think may be useful. Our support and development teams use this data to improve our products.

If you choose not to include diagnostic data with an error report, an anonymous record of the type of error which occurred will be sent. This allows us to measure how many of our customers experience errors and prioritize our focus for product development. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute our legitimate interests. We store your data for 3 years

#### 2.10. Applying for a role with us

If you apply for a role at 3T, we will use all the information you provide to assess your application. In most cases this will be at least your name, address, birth date and your cv. If you are unsuccessful in your application, we will remove your data after 6 months. The legal basis is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. We may ask your permission to keep your details on file in our talent pool on the legal basis of Art. 6 par. 1 lit. a) GDPR. We store this data until you withdraw your consent.

#### 2.11. How we use cookies

Your web browser allows you to control whether cookies can be stored by our websites. However, disabling cookies will prevent certain parts of our websites from working correctly. Your web browser’s documentation has more information on controlling cookie behavior.

We use cookies on our websites to:

  * Maintain your active session
  * Store your preferences
  * Track the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns
  * Analyze the way people use our websites
  * Gather data on how our websites are performing

Our use of cookies is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The mentioned purposes also constitute our legitimate interest. For a detailed information on the analytics, tracking and advertising tools and the respective possibilities to opt-out, please refer to Section 11.

### 3\. Recipients of personal data

Internally, we process your personal data in the relevant department. Externally, we use selected third parties to help us process data, which helps us deliver our products and services to you. Specifically, we use service providers to run our online shop, to send you emails, to provide you with the Site’s “Feedback & Support” tool and generally, to give you access to our site. If you ask for assistance, support or other services, your data may be processed by affiliated companies, which will provide the services directly to you.

We do not sell any data regarding your use of our products or services except as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets of 3T. In such case, we will ensure that your privacy continues to be protected.

### 4\. Transferring your information outside of the European Economic Area

Some of our service providers reside outside of the EU, especially in the USA. These service providers are either EU-US-Privacy Shield certified or we concluded standard contractual clauses approved by the EU Commission with such providers. You can obtain a copy of the standard contractual clauses texts on the website of the Commission ([https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en)).

### 5\. Your rights

If the respective requirements are met, the GDPR grants you certain rights as a data subject.

– **Art. 15 GDPR – Right of access:** You shall have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning you are being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and certain information.

– **Art. 16 GDPR – Right to rectification:** You shall have the right to obtain from us without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.

– **Art. 17 GDPR – Right to erasure:** You shall have the right to obtain from us the erasure of personal data concerning you without undue delay.

– **Art. 18 GDPR – Right to restriction of processing:** You shall have the right to obtain from us the restriction of processing.

– **Art. 20 GDPR – Right to data portability:** You shall have the right to receive the personal data concerning you, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and you shall have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from us. You shall also have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from us to another controller, where technically feasible.

– **Art. 21 GDPR – Right to object:** You shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you, which is based on legitimate interests or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller

In such case, we shall no longer process the personal data unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interests, rights and freedoms or where the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

Where personal data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the you shall have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning you for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.

– **Art. 77 GDPR – Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority:** Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you shall have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if you consider that the processing of personal data relating to you infringes the GDPR.

Where the processing is based on your informed consent, you shall have the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. Therefore, you may send us a message to [privacy@studio3t.com](mailto:privacy@studio3t.com).

### 6\. Your obligation to provide us with personal data

You have no statutory or contractual obligation to provide us with any personal data. However, we may not be able to provide you with our services if you decide not to do so.

### 7\. Existence of automated decision-making, including profiling

We do not use automated decision-making, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you.

### 8\. Questions about data privacy

If you have any questions regarding this policy, or wish to make a complaint about the way we’ve handled your personal information, contact [privacy@studio3t.com](mailto:privacy@studio3t.com)

### 9\. Miscellaneous

We encourage the responsible disclosure of security issues, and will act quickly on any vulnerabilities reported. We will not take legal action against you if you:

  * Provide us with the information needed to reproduce and validate the vulnerability
  * Avoid violating the privacy of our customers, staff and other users
  * Avoid the destruction of data, or degradation of our services
  * Do not modify or access data that is not your own
  * Give us a reasonable time to address the issue before making any information public

### 10\. Changes to this privacy policy

We regularly review our privacy policy. This policy was last updated on 11th July 2018.

### 11\. Tools used on our website for analytics, marketing and other purposes

#### 11.1. Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google“) to collect information about how users use our Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. As IP-anonymization is activated, your IP address will be anonymized as soon as technically feasible at the earliest possible stage of the collection network. In addition, it will only be partially used within the European Union or just in the European Economic Area if it is used by other parties. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be transferred to a Google server in the United States, and then shortened so it is only partially used there.

Google will use this information on our behalf for the purpose of analyzing your use of the Site, compiling reports on the website activity and providing other services relating to activity on the Site and internet usage. The IP address that your browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; please note, however, that if you do this you may not be able to use our service comprehensively. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics in the future by downloading and installing ‘Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on’ for your current web browser: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it. The collected data is stored for 50 months. Further information on how Google processes personal data is available at: <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>.

#### 11.2. BingAds

We use Bing Ads Universal Event Tracking, a conversion tracking service of the Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA (“Microsoft”). The service enables us to track your activities, if you accessed our site by clicking on a bing advertisement. For this purpose, Microsoft stores a cookie on your device. By using this cookie, Microsoft and we can see the total number of users that clicked on the ad. This data is stored by Microsoft for 180 days. We have no access to any personal information about you.

If you do not want to be tracked, you can opt-out under the following link: <https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=286759>. Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it. For further information, please click here: <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement/>.

#### 11.3. Quora Ads

We use Quora Ads, a service of Quora, Inc. This function enables Quora to show you our advertising within the Quora network. For this purpose, Quora will establish a direct connection between you and its servers and collect data about your use of our website. Quora may relate this data to your user account. We have neither knowledge of nor a possibility to influence the data processing by Quora. You can find more information on how Quora processes your data in its privacy policy under https://www.quora.com/about/privacy.

Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interest we pursue with it. If you want to opt-out, please change the respective settings in your user profile on Quora: <https://www.quora.com/optout>.

#### 11.4 HubSpot

We use the services of HubSpot (HubSpot Ireland Ltd., 2nd Floor 30 North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland, Telefon: +353 1 5187500 “HubSpot”). HubSpot tracks visitors using browser cookies. Every time a visitor lands on our website, HubSpot will check for an existing tracking cookie. If one does not exist, a cookie will be associated with that visitor and will log every page that person visits moving forward. Visitors will be tracked anonymously. If a visitor fills out a form, HubSpot will associate their previous page views based on the tracking cookie. Visitors will be tracked anonymously even before they become contacts. We use this data to analyze and improve our website and services in order to make them more appealing to you. HubSpot transfers personal data to the HubSpot Inc., which processes the data within the United States of America, however, HubSpot Inc. is certified under the EU-US-Privacy Shield. Hence, an adequate level of protection is ensured.

Our processing of your personal data is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes also constitute the legitimate interest we pursue with it. The personal data will be retained for the period of time outlined in section 2 of this Privacy Policy.

#### 11.5 Hotjar

We use [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device’s IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).
